<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Maxime NEMO - Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maxime NEMO - Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 17:40:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Drag and Drop using hand</title>
      <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/virtualdraganddrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 17:40:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/virtualdraganddrop/</guid>
      <description>VirtualDragAndDrop This programs create a virtual drag and drop on objects represented by their centers. I used rectangle for this example.
To use the program, just run the file main.py. Then to move an object, you have to &amp;ldquo;grab it&amp;rdquo; = close your hand when your hand is on the object. Then opening your hand will release the object.
I used Python with OpenCV and cvzone to detect the hand. A next step would be to recreate the hand detection by myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optique NEMO website</title>
      <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/optiquenemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 21:01:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/optiquenemo/</guid>
      <description>[Work in progress] Link : XXXXXXX I am building this website using WordPress and JavaScript. The project was not only building the website, but also to host it and I will be maintaining it. I am also responsible for Optique NEMO&amp;rsquo;s social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge DATA &amp; AI by Ens&#39;IA and Neovision</title>
      <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/challenge_data_ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:05:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/challenge_data_ia/</guid>
      <description>The challenge: This challenge is about the well known subject of Optical Character Recognition (OCR).
The goal is quite simple : building the best model to recognize the characters in the dataset given by Neovision. (private dataset)
The results: My team managed to end in second position with a macro-averaged accuracy of 0.78.
The model: My model is available in my github (french version). https://github.com/MaximeNe/Challenge-DATA-IA
We tried different methods. We worked on transfer learning, on image preprocessing, on segmentation, etc&amp;hellip; The best result used transfer learning with ImageNet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jpeg decoder</title>
      <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/jpeg_decoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:29:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/jpeg_decoder/</guid>
      <description>The project This project is about building a functional JPEG to PPM decoder. We worked together with two teammates to build this using the C language. This program can process multiple JPEG images in baseline sequential mode (non progressive).
Because I am not the only one owner of this code, I will not publish it. However, you can contact me to access the code.
How it works JPEG format compress images using mathematical methods and algorithms that are described on the official JPEG documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size of Connex Components in unoriented 2D graph</title>
      <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/connex_components/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 23:02:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/connex_components/</guid>
      <description>The project Considering a set of points p_i, 1&amp;lt;i&amp;lt;n, and a limit distance s, we want to know the number a connex component. Two vertices p_i and p_j are linked by an edge if d(p_i, p_j) &amp;lt;= s.
A connex component is a sub-graph where all the vertices are linked by transitivity.
A solution I worked in pair with ELHAJ-LAHSEN Hugo on different methods. We studied quadtrees, M-trees, VP-trees, Divide-and-conquer algorithm, optimization &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TodoList implementation</title>
      <link>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/todolist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:01:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximene.github.io/AboutMe.github.io/posts/todolist/</guid>
      <description>The project I always wanted to have a todolist on my desktop (I use Gnome). I made few research for widget on the internet, did not find what I was looking for, so I decided to make my own.
I wanted something that does not consume too much power, that is easy to use (as fast as possible to add something in a terminal) and free.
What I built I have chosen to create a todolist that actually changes the background of my computer, so that the consumption of my todolist is down to 0 when I am not changing anything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
